Marielle Nwana

linkedin.com/in/mnwana (#)
mariellenwana@gmail.com (#)

New York City NY (*)

My name is Marielle Nwana and I'm an NYC-based technologist. I've spent the last four years building a deep understanding of data analysis, with a focus on technical skills. Through those experiences, I've found that I'm a self-starter who is comfortable navigating ambiguity in high-growth environments to drive key results. I'm passionate about using technology to automate manual tasks and provide end users with useful tools and information.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Database & EngineeringProgrammingVisualizationProject ManagementData SciencePostgreSQL, AirflowPython, Java, WebLooker, Tableau,Jira, Clubhouse,Pandas, Scikit-Learn,Snowflake, BigQuery, dbtMining, AutomationGoogle Data StudioAsana, GitHubR, NumPy

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tula Skincare / Nov 2021 - Present / Senior Growth Analyst

- Support conversion optimization through site analytics tracking and event analysis using Snowflake, BigQuery, and Google Analytics
- Partner with Growth Marketing to track, report, and analyze new customer acquisition efforts using Snowflake and Looker

Flowcode / Oct 2019 - Nov 2021 / Tech Lead - Business Intelligence

- Built out external client reporting in partnership with client success managers to ensure scalable insights and analysis across 80 customers using Python, Snowflake and Github and Looker APIs
- Worked cross-functionally to provide internal business units with insights in order to understand changes in key internal metrics using Looker, SQL, and custom Airflow pipelines

Essence Digital / May 2018 - Oct 2019 / Senior Data Analyst - Machine Learning

Led research in attention signals for programmatic ad bidding and campaign optimization, created an ETL workflow for collecting data to feed client-facing dashboards, and analyzed social media data for campaign optimization research

L Brands - La Senza / May 2017 - Aug 2017 / Central Planning Intern

Automated sales planning projections & reporting using VBA to save 20 hours per month and reduce input errors.

Huntington National Bank / May 2016 - Aug 2016 / Analytics Intern

Automated collection of competitor data using Selenium and Python to save 10 hours per week and provide more accessible benchmarks against other regional financial institutions.

EDUCATION

Master of Science - Stevens Institute of Technology / Aug 2018 - Dec 2019

Business Intelligence & Analytics with Data Science Concentration: Coursework included experimental design, optimization and process analysis, multivariate analysis, data mining, data warehousing, social network analysis, machine learning, and web mining

Bachelor of Science - Ohio State University / Aug 2013 - Dec 2017

Data Analytics with Business Specialization: Coursework included computational, mathematical and statistical foundations of data analytics